Kathryn Herod

Mid-Senior Front End Software Engineer in Houston, TX codingkat7@gmail.com | 1-281-989-4865 | kathrynherod.com

Profile

Experienced front-end software developer with expertise in code quality, user experience, accessibility, testing, and maintenance of Enterprise and Legacy software systems. Excels in collaborating with product managers, designers, and stakeholders to understand user needs and build software to meet those needs.

Employment History

Front End Developer & Scrum Master at Identity Automation, Remote

September 2020 — Present & October 2018 — April 2020

Skills: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ember JS, JQuery, Git, Bootstrap, Material, Qunit (unit, integration, & acceptance testing), REST APIs, JSON, Java, Postgres, Docker, AWS, GitLab

- Practiced servant leadership style by helping the engineering team embrace agile core values and principles, which resulted in teams doubling their previous velocities and producing monthly software releases, versus quarterly releases
- Boosted customer retention and referrals by working closely with product managers, customers, support, and developers to scope and refine requirements for our Rostering software
- On-boarded, up-skilled and mentored over 10 junior developers, offshore resource teams, and new hires and created corresponding documentation to reduce onboarding time from nearly two weeks, to a few days
- Delivered, supported, and maintained clean, readable, and commented code using the Ember JS framework, making the software accessible and responsive for users on various browsers and devices
- Increased overall test coverage within the front-end codebase from less than 30% to over 60% by implementing SonarQube tooling
- Set minimum testing requirements on new code to 75% coverage, which led to fewer bugs and regressions in releases and a test driven development mindset on the team

UI/UX Engineer at O'Reilly Auto Parts, Remote

April 2020 — September 2020

Skills: Java, JavaFX, HTML, CSS, Git, AdobeXD

- Helped create and maintain a design system for the retail point of sale division, which ensured styling consistencies across several development teams
- Worked closely with business analysts and other developers to ensure new prototypes met the standards of the new design system and assisted with documenting existing inconsistencies
- Created reusable JavaFX components for the design system, leading to increased velocities on development sprint teams
- Rapid prototyped new features to support stakeholders in visualizing design documents and fine tuning ticket requirements, saving colleagues hours each week during sprint planning ceremonies

Software Engineer Senior Analyst at Accenture, Houston, TX

December 2017 — October 2018

Skills: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, React, Angular, JQuery, Git, Bootstrap, Material, Mocha, Cypress, Jest, REST APIs, JSON

- Worked as a front-end developer within various full-stack scrum teams to rapid prototype SPAs for clients
- Created mockups and interactive wireframes for legacy software redesign
- Orchestrated software design thinking sessions for clients
- Collaborated with a small team to facilitate workspace culture engagement and activities

Entrepreneur, Pastry Chef, and Cooking Instructor at Well Done Cooking Classes, Houston, TX

January 2009 — September 2018

Skills: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Drupal, PHP, REST APIs, Bootstrap

- Launched company teaching cooking classes which grew to \$600,000/year revenue business before selling in late 2018
- Monitored all spending to identify inefficient processes and best performing products/classes to focus on
- Implemented detailed instruction and humor to teach thousands of people with internationally diverse backgrounds and skill levels
- Crafted several private events for large corporations and their C-Suite executives, such as ABB, C-Panel, Ford, Shell
- Created and designed 200 cooking classes and an accredited sixteen-week professional chef training program
- Authored over 250 recipes detailing step-by-step instructions for both employees and cooking class clients
- Incorporated project management abilities and communication skills to lead thirty-two people to work together and enjoy elaborate meals in three hours or less
- Frequently asked to appear on local news and national television programs such as "The Little Couple", "Great Day Houston", and "Guy's Grocery Games"
- Continually redesigned the front-end of our website for responsiveness and page load efficiency as technologies
 evolved
- Integrated Authorize.net APIs for a custom e-commerce system and met yearly PCI compliance standards, resulting in faster and more secure checkouts
- Researched trends and consulted with customers to enhance UX on our website, leading to fewer calls related to website confusion
- Used SEO keyword marketing to create descriptions of cooking classes on our website, which increased search traffic and sales and led to becoming the first results on location based searches
- Effectively solved problems in a fast-paced, high-stress environment, the kitchen

Education

Bachelor of Arts, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

September 2003 — December 2007

Hobbies

- Playing French Horn in local orchestras
- Adoption coordinator and foster for a local German Shepherd Rescue
- Woodworking